<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Clonezilla - Tag - Kuldeep</title><link>https://kuldeep.tech/tags/clonezilla/</link><description>Clonezilla - Tag - Kuldeep</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hi@kuldeep.tech (Kuldeep)</managingEditor><webMaster>hi@kuldeep.tech (Kuldeep)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:06:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kuldeep.tech/tags/clonezilla/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Backup With Clonezilla: Part-I(Backup)</title><link>https://kuldeep.tech/posts/basic-backup-with-clonezilla/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:06:59 +0530</pubDate><author><name>Kuldeep</name></author><guid>https://kuldeep.tech/posts/basic-backup-with-clonezilla/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/posts/basic-backup-with-clonezilla/featured-image-preview.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>I like to try out new things and experiment with my systems quite a lot, and because of that, sometimes things break or don&rsquo;t quite work as expected. Sometimes it&rsquo;s a compatibility issue or because I messed up something. And that has sometimes cost me a lot of unnecessary effort and time.</p>
<p>I mostly never have to worry about most of my data, as I keep backups for most of it, or they are on cloud storage that I keep in sync with my local storage. It&rsquo;s the state of my system that sometimes throws me off-guard, like, for instance, when I won&rsquo;t be able to boot because my new arch update had an issue with my bootloader, or sometimes a software update breaks in some unexpected way and I have to figure out what&rsquo;s wrong and fix it. So I like to keep a backup of my system state so that I can restore it to a working state if something goes wrong, and I need it to work as soon as possible. And that backup is mostly a disk image of my system with minimal things installed and configured. For that, up until now I&rsquo;ve used g-parted and <code>dd</code> for the most part, which are fairly basic and dumb utilities and work great. There are other, more advanced solutions out there, like Timeshift and Snapper, but they require a lot more setup and some insight into filesystems. For the most part, in my use  case, I just want my system back up and running if I happen to break it. For the most part, I don&rsquo;t require point-in-time backups or incremental backups.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>